Finding aid for the J. Paul Getty Museum Getty Villa Public Event Recordings, 2006-2018 IA20035
Institutional Records and Archives
J. Paul Getty Museum Getty Villa public event recordings
2006-2018
Institutional Records and Archives
J. Paul Getty Museum. Villa Program Coordination
J. Paul Getty Museum. Public Programs Villa
IA20035
12.6 Linear Feet (35 boxes)
26.49 GB (77 digital files; 134 DVDs and 22 CDs that have not been reformatted)
This collection consists of audiovisual recordings and ephemera of public programming events sponsored by the J. Paul Getty Museum that were held at the Getty Villa campus from 2006 to 2018. Events comprise lectures, conversations, panel discussions, symposia, seminars, colloquia, and workshops with curators, scholars, conservators, artists, and museum professionals. They were organized by the Museum's department of Public Programs at the Getty Villa. Recordings include born-digital files stored on CDs, DVDs, and Getty servers.
Acquisition Information
The records originated in accessions 2008.IA.33, 2009.IA.21, 2010.IA.13, 2011.IA.02, 2012.IA.29, 2014.IA.11, 2015.IA.50, 2016.IA.52, 2017.IA.91, and 2018.IA.81.
2006-2007
2008.IA.33
2008
2008.IA.33 and 2009.IA.21
2009
2009.IA.21
2010
2010.IA.13 and 2011.IA.02
2011
2011.IA.02
2012
2012.IA.29 and 2014.IA.11
2013
2014.IA.11
2014
2014.IA.11 and 2015.IA.50
2015
2015.IA.50
2016
2016.IA.52
2017
2017.IA.91
2018
2018.IA.81
Restrictions on Access
The records described in accessions 2008.IA.33, 2009.IA.21, 2010.IA.13, 2011.IA.02, 2012.IA.29, 2014.IA.11, 2015.IA.50, 2016.IA.52, 2017.IA.91, and 2018.IA.81 are available for use by qualified researchers.
To request access to recordings, fill out the reference form with the event title and associated accession number. Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
Some recordings are digitized but are restricted to on-site access only.
Scope and Content of Collection
This collection consists of audiovisual recordings of public programming events sponsored by the J. Paul Getty Museum that were held at the Getty Villa campus from 2006 to 2018. Related ephemera is present for select events dated from 2006 to 2013.
Events comprise scholarly lectures, seminars, workshops, colloquia, and symposia conducted by experts in their particular fields. The collection represents the forefront of academic thought on such matters as ancient Greece, Rome, and Etruria. Events also present complementary themes related to current Getty exhibitions, initiatives, and the permanent collection, as well as interdisciplinary topics related to the activities of the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Getty Research Institute, the Getty Conservation Institute, and the Getty Foundation.
Events were organized by the Museum's department of Public Programs at the Getty Villa. Recordings include born-digital files stored on CDs, DVDs, and Getty servers. Ephemera may include the following: event programs or schedules, abstracts of lectures, or brief biographies of participants. Select events include links to webcasts available on getty.edu.
Arrangement
Events are grouped chronologically by calendar year. Within each year, recordings are arranged chronologically by event date. Recordings that are part of a programming series are listed first. Ephemera is listed with its associated event recording in this finding aid, but housed separately from the recordings.
Administrative History
The Getty Villa, located just off the Pacific Coast Highway in Pacific Palisades, California, operates as a museum and educational center dedicated to the study of the arts and cultures of ancient Greece, Rome, and Etruria. The Getty Villa was designed to house J. Paul Getty's art collection when it outgrew his Ranch House, which had served as a private museum since 1954. After considering various options for expanding the Ranch House, Getty decided in the fall of 1968 to build a new museum on the same property, in the form of a first-century Roman country house, based primarily on the plans of the ancient Villa dei Papiri just outside of Herculaneum. The archaeologist Norman Neuerburg, who had studied the ruins of Herculaneum and was an authority on Roman domestic architecture, was retained as a consultant for the project. The Santa Monica architectural firm Langdon and Wilson was hired to design the Villa, and British architect Stephen Garrett, who had served as Getty's consultant in the remodeling of a Getty home in Posillipo, Italy, was retained as overseer of the construction. Landscape architect Emmet Wemple designed the gardens, artist Garth Benton painted the murals, and consultant Bruce Ptolemy designed the fountains. The construction itself was done by Dinwiddie Construction Co., with various subcontractors. Construction began on December 21, 1970, and the new museum opened to the public on January 16, 1974.
As part of the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Villa is overseen by the J. Paul Getty Trust, an international cultural and philanthropic organization serving both general audiences and specialized professionals. The Trust is a not-for-profit institution, educational in purpose and character, that focuses on the visual arts in all of their dimensions. As of 2019 the Trust supports and oversees four programs: the Getty Research Institute, the Getty Foundation, the Getty Conservation Institute, and the J. Paul Getty Museum. Beginning in the 1980s the Trust developed an expansion plan that included the Getty Center campus in Brentwood and the renovation and expansion of the Villa in Pacific Palisades. When the Getty Center opened in 1997, the Villa closed to undergo extensive remodeling. The architectural firm of Machado and Silvetti Associates redesigned the Villa, and it reopened on January 28, 2006. While most of the Museum's collections are housed at the Getty Center, the antiquities collection is housed at the Villa. The Getty Villa serves a varied audience through the permanent collection, changing exhibitions, conservation, scholarship, research, and public programs in an intimate setting overlooking the Pacific Ocean. A reinstallation of the permanent collections began in 2017; the new, chronological presentation was opened to the public on April 18, 2018.
The history of public programming at the Getty dates to the Museum's earliest years, with public lectures regularly held at the Ranch House and the Getty Villa. The Museum offered a limited selection of other public events, including theatrical productions and music performances. The opening of the Getty Center in 1997 initiated a wide-sweeping, programmatic effort to integrate public events with the museum-going experience.
With the goal of broadening the Museum's audience, the institution developed a number of ongoing series, as well as regularly scheduled individual events, focusing on scholarly topics, gallery tours, and the performing arts. Series launched in 1998 that continue at the Getty Center include Sounds of L.A., Selected Shorts, Friday Nights at the Getty (which have since moved to Saturdays), and the Gordon Getty Concerts, named in honor of J. Paul Getty's son and former Trustee Gordon Getty. Since the reopening of the Villa in 2006, visitors have had the opportunity to enjoy theatrical performances in the classical tradition at the Barbara and Lawrence Fleischman Outdoor Classical Theater. As of 2019, the Museum offers a variety of events for children and adults, including artist projects, demonstrations, courses, tours, lectures, symposia, and a host of performances at both the Getty Center and Getty Villa.
Public Programming responsiblities were historically undertaken by the Museum's Education Department, with a designated Performing Arts Manager joining the Getty in 1999. In 2001, the performing arts program moved to the renamed Exhibitions and Public Programs Department; by 2008, it had returned to the auspices of the Education Department. In 2016, Public Programs became a department within the newly expanded division of Education, Public Programs, and Interpretive Media (renamed Interpretive Content in 2018).
Related Materials
The following materials are offered as possible sources of further information on the agencies and subjects covered by the records. The listing is not exhaustive.
Getty Institutional Archives
J. Paul Getty Museum Getty Center Public Event Recordings, 1998-2018, undated. The Getty Research Institute (IA20037).
J. Paul Getty Museum Public Programs Performing Arts Recordings and Ephemera, 1998-2018. The Getty Research Institute (IA40012).
Getty Research Institute Public Event Records and Recordings, 1998-2020. The Getty Research Institute (IA40002).
Ephemera; Sound recordings; Video recordings; DVDs; Art, Roman; Art, Greek; Classical antiquities; Lectures; Compact discs; Art museums -- Educational aspects; Electronic records (digital records); Getty Villa (Malibu, Calif.)
- 2006 Events
  Access Restrictions
  Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2008.IA.33. Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
  - "Travelers, Scholars and Photographers View the Ancient World" lecture by Andrew Szegedy-Maszak, February 23, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Laocoon: The Discovery, Fortunes, and Interpretations of a Hidden Masterpiece" lecture by Luca Giuliani, March 2, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Ancient Marbles at the Getty Villa: A History of Use and Provenance" lecture by Lorenzo Lazzarini, March 9, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Egypt Recovered: Early Photographic Surveys and the Development of Egyptology" lecture by Kathleen Howe, March 30, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - Architecture at the Getty Villa: roundtable discussion, April 5, 2006
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "The Getty Villa Reimagined" lecture by Jorge Silvetti, April 6, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Taste for the Antique: Collecting Marbles in Liguria" seminar by Elena Calandra, April 12, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Inside Out, Outside In: Landscape, Architecture, and the Getty Villa" lecture by Wim de Wit, April 20, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Commodus: Ancient or Modern?" lecture by Miranda Marvin, April 30, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Gardens of the Roman World" lecture by Patrick Bowe, May 18, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "The Colors of Clay: Special Techniques in Athenian Vases" lecture by Beth Cohen, June 15, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "The Colors of Clay: Special Techniques in Athenian Vases" symposium, June 16-17, 2006
    - Event recordings, (set of 5 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "Fragrance of Rose and Flavor of Mint: Flowers and Herbs in Ancient Roman Gardens" lecture by Marina Heilmeyer, June 29, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Finding the Villa dei Papiri at Herculaneum" lecture by Carol Mattusch, July 13, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Beyond Black and Red: Athenian Vases in Special Techniques" lecture by Kenneth Lapatin, August 3, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Reimagining Euripiedes' Hippolytos" lecture by Helene Foley, September 21, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Religion and Ritual: From Ancient Greece to Contemporary America" lecture by Jan Bremmer, October 5, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Images of Hippolytos and Phaedra in Ancient Art" lecture by Pascale Linant de Bellefonds, October 12, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-5)
  - "Ritual and Money Among the Ancient Greeks" lecture by Richard Seaford, October 27, 2006; (1 audiodisc: CD-ROM) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "The Gran Ruta Inca: A Force for Andean Integration" lecture by Ricardo Espinosa, December 7, 2006; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
- 2007 Events
  - "Pagan Sculpture in Late Antiquity: Between Destruction and Preservation" lecture by Ortwin Dally, January 11, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Puzzling Images" lecture by Christine Kondoleon, February 1, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Greek Tragedy: Why Do We Still Care?" lecture by Jasper Griffin, March 1, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Mosaics Conservation" panel discussion, March 8, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Rites of Passage of the Life Cycle of Antiquity" symposium, April 20-21, 2007
    - Event recordings, (set of 9 videodiscs: DVDs) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "The Pergamon Altar: Sacrificial Site, Hero Tomb, or Victory Monument?" lecture by Andreas Scholl, April 23, 2007; (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
    Note
    Recording cuts off before end of the lecture.
  - "Conserving Mosaics of Tunisia" lecture by Aicha Ben Abed, April 26, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Human Sacrifice: Myth, Reality, and Representation" workshop, May 18, 2007; (set of 4 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "The New Hellenistic and Roman Galleries at the Metropolitan Museum of Art" lecture by Carlos Picon, June 9, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "Exploring Roman Temple Gardens: New Perspectives from Pompeii" lecture by Maureen Carroll, July 12, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-6)
  - "The Theater of Herculaneum and the Origins of Archaeology" lecture by Christopher Parslow, July 29, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Plautus' Rudens: The Challenge of Presenting Classical Theater to Modern Audiences" discussion with Amy Richlin, Meryl Friedman, and Ann Steinsapir, September 29, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Identity Theft in the Ancient Mediterranean World" lecture by Erich Gruen, October 4, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Foundation Legends and Cultural Integration in the Ancient Mediterranean" colloquium, November 9, 2007
    - Event recordings, (set of 4 videodiscs: DVDs) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
      Note:
      DVDs are labled Disc 1, 2, 3, and 5, skipping number 4.
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "World Heritage in the 21st Century" lecture by Francesco Bandarin, November 29, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "The Roman Triumph: The Dangers of Winning a War" lecture by Mary Beard, December 3, 2007; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
- 2008 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2008.IA.33. For the event dated November 7, 2008, use accession number 2009.IA.21. Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
  - "Copiez la femme: Replicated Bodies and Individuality in Roman Portraiture" lecture by Annetta Alexandridis, January 10, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Technique and Technology: Reproducing Roman Glass in the 19th Century" lecture by Michael Klein and Dunja Kobel-Klein, January 12, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "The Marriage of Venice and Rome: What Makes Piranesi Great" lecture by Andrew Robison, February 10, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Roman Statues, Rabbis, and Graeco-Roman Art" lecture by Yaron Eliav, February 28, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "The Magnificent Piranesi" discussion with Marcia Reed, Louis Marchesano and Erika Naginski, March 1, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Writing Historical Fiction: The Ancient World in Modern Literature," a conversation with Steven Saylor and Steven Pressfield, moderated by Patt Morrison, March 6, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
    - Webcast
  - "Representations of the Alien" colloquium, March 14, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "New Reflections on the Derveni Krater and its Macedonian Context" lecture by Beryl Barr-Sharrar, April 17, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Color in Classical Sculpture: A Challenge to Western Ideals" lecture by Jan Stubbe Ostergaard, May 1, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-8)
  - "Rediscovering Color: New Perspectives on Polychrome Sculpture" symposium, May 2, 2008
    Session 1 was not recorded because the speaker did not consent to being audio or video recorded.
    - Event recordings, (set of 8 videodiscs: DVDs) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "Pericles of Athens and the Dangers of Democracy" lecture by Loren J. Samons, June 5, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
    - Webcast (audio)
  - "Reconstructing Identity" workshop, June 21, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
    - Ephemera (Box 2008.IA.33-7 (temp vault 1 Ill shelves))
  - "Getting to Know Herakleides: Exploring a Red-Shroud Mummy from Roman Egypt" lecture by Marie Svoboda, July 12, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
    - Webcast
  - "Hearst and the Antique: A Larger Context for the Hope Hygieia" lecture by Mary Levkoff, July 19, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
  - "Ruins and Revelry: The Society of Dilettanti" lecture by Charles Sebag-Montefiore, September 13, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
  - "Dilettanti: The Antic and the Antique in Eighteenth-Century England" lecture by Bruce Redford, September 20, 2008; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2008.IA.33-9)
  - "In Conversation with Jim Dine,", November 7, 2008
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
    - Webcast
- 2009 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2009.IA.21. Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
  - "Commodus: A Gladiator-God Ruling Rome" lecture by Olivier Hekster, January 22, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Magical Gemstones" colloquium, February 13, 2009
    - Event recordings, (set of 4 audiodiscs: CD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
    - Ephemera (Box 2009.IA.21-3)
  - "Balancing Fact and Fiction: The Ancient World of HBO's 'Rome'," a conversation with Jonathan Stamp and Patt Morrison, March 5, 2009
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
    - Webcast
  - "The Archaeological Discoveries at Sagalassos: Revelations about Life in an Ancient Roman City" lecture by Marc Waelkens, March 12, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Passion for the Antique: Sex, Lies, and Theft in Late 18th-Century Europe" lecture by Gerard Vaughan, March 26, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Taste for the Antique in Modern Europe" colloquium, March 27, 2009
    - Event recording, (1 audiodisc: CD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
    - Ephemera (Box 2009.IA.21-3)
  - "Royal Fake: A Collection of 'Ancient' Gemstones for Prince Poniatowski" lecture by Gertrud Platz-Horster, March 28, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Mythical Stones: The Appeal of Engraved Gems in the Age of Augustus" lecture by Dimitris Plantzos, April 2, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "The Enigma of the Pantheon: Old Problems, New Answers, and Continuing Speculation" lecture by Mark Wilson Jones, April 23, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Bringing It All Back Home: Grand Tour Collections at Castle Howard in the 18th Century" lecture by Christopher Ridgeway, April 25, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Restoring the Past" discussion with Miranda Marvin and Jerry Podany, moderated by David Bomford, April 30, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Alexander or Antinous? The many faces of a Roman Statue" lecture by Jens Daehner, May 28, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-1)
  - "Greek Art / Roman Eyes: The Reception of Greek Art in the Private Sphere in Ancient Italy" symposium, June 5-6, 2009
    - Event recordings, (set of 5 videodiscs: DVDs) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
    - Ephemera (Box 2009.IA.21-3)
  - "Peace Talk: A Conversation with Culture Clash,", October 3, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
  - "Herculaneum: Conserving and Interpreting the Roman Past" lecture by Gionata Rizzi, October 24, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
  - "Ruins between East and West" lecture by Alain Schnapp, October 29, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
  - "The Poison King: Mithradates the Great" lecture by Adrienne Mayor, November 4, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
  - "Narrative, Myth, and Society in Early Etruscan Culture" lecture by Giovannangelo Camporeale, December 3, 2009; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2009.IA.21-4)
  - "Myth, Allegory, Emblem: The Many Lives of the Chimaera of Arezzo" colloquium, December 4-5, 2009
    - Event recordings, (set of 4 videodiscs: DVDs) (Box 2009.IA.21-5)
    - Ephemera (Box 2009.IA.21-3)
- 2010 Events
  Access copies of recordings on discs must be created prior to use. To request access, fill out the reference form with the event title and accession number 2010.IA.13. For the event dated December 2, 2010, use accession number 2011.IA.02.
  Please note reformatting may take up to eight weeks.
  - "Earthquake, Volcano, Tsunami: Natural Disasters and Political Change" lecture by Joseph Alexander "Sandy" MacGillivray, February 6, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
  - "Collecting with Mr. Getty," a conversation with Burton Fredericksen, Stephen Garrett and Gillian Wilson, January 16, 2010
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
    - Webcast
  - "Tracking the Cosmos: The Technology of the Antikythera Mechanism," a discussion with Jo Marchant, James Evans, and Patt Morrison, March 4, 2010
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
    - Webcast
  - "Merida: The Archaeological Discovery of Augusta Emerita, a Roman Capital in Spain" lecture by Trinidad Nogales Basarrate, April 8, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
  - "Nahua Artists and the Aztec Legacy in the Florentine Codex" lecture by Diana Magaloni Kerpel, April 29, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
  - "Altera Roma: Art and Empire from the Aztecs to New Spain" symposium, April 30-May 1, 2010
    - Event recordings, (set of 6 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-2)
    - Ephemera: Event program (Box 2010.IA.13-3)
  - "Envisioning a New World" lecture by Mary Miller, June 2, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
  - "The Niobid Painter in Athens" lecture by J. Michael Padgett, July 14, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
  - "Artists and Actors: Iconography and Performance in Ancient Greece" symposium, September 24-25, 2010
    - Event recordings, (set of 7 videodiscs: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
    - Ephemera: Event program (Box 2010.IA.13-3)
  - "Of Pots and Pits: Excavating the Gardens of The Roman Empire" lecture by Cathryn Gleason, October 9, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
  - "William Randolph Hearst and J. Paul Getty: Collectors of Antiquities" lecture by Victoria Castner, October 16, 2010
    - Event recording, (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
    - Webcast
  - "Art and Performance in Classical Greece" lecture by Mary Louise Hart, October 30, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2010.IA.13-4)
  - "The Origins of Hellenistic Ruler Portraiture in the Philippeion at Olympia" lecture by Peter Shultz, December 2, 2010; (1 videodisc: DVD) (Box 2011.IA.02-02)
- 2011 Events